# NIKUNJ JADHAV

nixkj3@gmail.com | +91 7977064992 | linktree/Nixk07 | linkedin/nikunj-jadhav

### **Profile**

A skilled DevOps engineer with **2+ years** of hands-on experience in enterprise-level IT Infrastructure Design, Continuous Integration, and Continuous Deployment (**CI/CD**) on **various cloud providers**.

Skills Certification

Programming Languages: C++, Java, Python, Bash

Databases: MySQL, SQL Services (SSIS, SSRS), phpMyAdmin

Version Control: Git. BitBucket

Web Development: **HTML5**, **CSS3**, **JS**,**PHP**, **Yii2**, **Flask** Python Libraries: **NumPy**, **Pandas**, **Seaborn**, **Matplotlib** 

Cloud Providers: AWS, Azure, GCP

Containerization (**Docker**)
Project management tool: **JIRA** 

Data Visualization Tableau, Power-Bl Data Analysis with Python | Dphi

Azure Fundamental
Credly Porfolio

PubSub+ Cloud:

Solace Certified Developer practitioner, Solace Certified EDA-practitioner, Solace Certified solutions consultant

# **Work Experience**

### **DevOps Engineer**

Solace, Mumbai

April 2024 - Current

- Working as a Junior DevOps Engineer, monitoring daily alerts for Segmentors and Queues using DataDog Monitoring Agent.
- Setting up **cron script** for **automation** of Daily alerts & monitoring the Uptime of the servers.
- Technologies: Solace, Bash, C, JS, DataDog, etc.

### **Cloud Associate**

April 2022 - September 2023

SaphhireInfoTech Ventures, Mumbai

- Worked as a **Cloud Associate**, creating daily reports in **Excel** & handling client mail & processing requests.
- Setting up application servers based on various requirements on the cloud while doing on-prem to cloud migration.
- I also helped create **disaster recovery plans** for various clients, ensuring efficient system operational recovery to their DR site during a catastrophic app failure.
- Technologies: Azure, VM, Storage, S2S, and more; AWS services include EC2, S3, Cloudwatch, VPC, Lambda, IAM, etc.

### Software Intern

February 2022 - April 2022

Synergy Technology, Mumbai

- Built a CRUD app with Admin Login, phpMyAdmin Database & Flask used with Foreign Key Tables for Music Webpage.
- I built the **plugin** from scratch, adding ease of use to the users. It's integrated into **WordPress**.
- Technologies: HTML, Javascript, WordPress, PHPMyAdmin, PHP 7, Yii2, Flask.

### **Web-Development Intern**

**February 2019 - March 2019** 

Sahu Technologies, Mumbai

- Designed Dynamic UI pages for Hotel management systems and Library Management Systems."
- Created a multi-page interactive website, linked it to a database, and deployed it using "PHPMyAdmin."
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHPMyAdmin.

# **Education**

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology (BSc-IT), Mumbai University

CGPA: 7.83/10 2019 - 2021

Diploma in Computer Science, Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education (MSBTE)

73% 2016 - 2019

### **Projects**

# Yoga Plus - IIT Bombay's EdTech Hackathon

- Developed an **Android** app & web app in **Flutter** that assists users in performing yoga and workouts by using machine learning models in **TensorFlow Lite**. The user's stats were stored in **Firebase**.
- The web app uses the webcam to capture images and infers poses using the MAX deep learning model
- Technologies: HTML, CSS3, Javascript, Tensorflow.js, PoseNet, Model Asset Exchange

### **SOS-Android App**

- Developed an **Android app** that triggers **SOS** via handset buttons without touching the phone screen
- It uses voice recognition to send an SMS when a certain word is spoken & then sends live location via SMS.
- Technologies: Java, Android Studio, XML, JDBC, and MS-SQL

# **Achievements**

# **Volunteering**

Youth Volunteer at HariPrabodham [2017- Present]

Stood 7th in the IIT Bombay EdTech Hackathon Stood 3rd in the Apscript Hackathon Selected in CII - Debate Competition, State-Wise